Once upon a time there were three Bears,
who lived together in a house of
their own, in a wood.
One of them was a Little Wee Bear, and one
was a Middle-sized Bear, and the
other was a Great Big Bear.
They had each a bowl for their porridge;
a little bowl for the Little Wee Bear;
and a middle-sized bowl for the
Middle-sized Bear;
and a great bowl for the Great Big Bear.
And they had each a chair to sit in;
a little chair for the Little Wee Bear;
and a middle-sized chair for the
Middle-sized Bear;
and a great chair for the Great Big Bear.
And they had each a bed to sleep in;
a little bed for the Little Wee Bear;
and a middle-sized bed for the
Middle-sized Bear;
and a great bed for the Great Big Bear.
One day, after they had made the porridge
for their breakfast, and poured it
into their porridge-bowls, they walked out
into the wood while the porridge
was cooling, that they might not burn
their mouths by beginning too soon, for
they were polite, well-brought-up Bears.
And while they were away a little girl
called Goldilocks, who lived at the
other side of the wood and had been sent
on an errand by her mother, passed by
the house, and looked in at the window.
And then she peeped in at the keyhole, for
she was not at all a well-brought-
up little girl. Then seeing nobody in the
house she lifted the latch.
The door was not fastened, because the
Bears were good Bears, who did nobody
any harm, and never suspected that anybody
would harm them.
So Goldilocks opened the door and went in;
and well pleased was she when she saw the
porridge on the table.
If she had been a well-brought-up little
girl she would have waited till the
Bears came home, and then, perhaps, they
would have asked her to breakfast;
for they were good Bears—a little rough or
so, as the manner of Bears is, but
for all that very good-natured and
hospitable.
But she was an impudent, rude little girl,
and so she set about helping
herself. First she tasted the porridge of
the Great Big Bear, and that was
too hot for her.
Next she tasted the porridge of the
Middle-sized Bear, but that was too cold
for her. And then she went to the porridge
of the Little Wee Bear, and tasted
it, and that was neither too hot nor too
cold, but just right, and she liked
it so well that she ate it all up, every
bit!
Then Goldilocks, who was tired, for she
had been catching butterflies instead
of running on her errand, sat down in the
chair of the Great Big Bear, but
that was too hard for her.
And then she sat down in the chair of the
Middle-sized Bear, and that was too
soft for her. But when she sat down in the
chair of the Little Wee Bear, that
was neither too hard nor too soft, but
just right.
So she seated herself in it, and there she
sat till the bottom of the chair
came out, and down she came, plump upon
the ground;
and that made her very cross, for she was
a bad-tempered little girl.
Now, being determined to rest, Goldilocks
went upstairs into the bedchamber in
which the Three Bears slept.
And first she lay down upon the bed of the
Great Big Bear, but that was too
high at the head for her.
And next she lay down upon the bed of the
Middle-sized Bear, and that was too
high at the foot for her.
And then she lay down upon the bed of the
Little Wee Bear, and that was
neither too high at the head nor at the
foot, but just right.
So she covered herself up comfortably, and
lay there till she fell fast asleep.
By this time the Three Bears thought their
porridge would be cool enough for
them to eat it properly;
so they came home to breakfast.
Now careless Goldilocks had left the spoon
of the Great Big Bear standing in
his porridge. "SOMEBODY HAS BEEN AT MY
PORRIDGE!"
said the Great Big Bear in his great,
rough, gruff voice.
Then the Middle-sized Bear looked at his
porridge and saw the spoon was
standing in it too. "
SOMEBODY HAS BEEN AT MY PORRIDGE!"
said the Middle-sized Bear in his
middle-sized voice.
Then the Little Wee Bear looked at his,
and there was the spoon in the
porridge-bowl, but the porridge was all
gone! "
SOMEBODY HAS BEEN AT MY PORRIDGE, AND HAS
EATEN IT ALL UP!"
said the Little Wee Bear in his little wee
voice.
Upon this the Three Bears, seeing that
some one had entered their house, and
eaten up the Little Wee Bear's breakfast,
began to look about them.
Now the careless Goldilocks had not put
the hard cushion straight when she
rose from the chair of the Great Big Bear.
"
SOMEBODY HAS BEEN SITTING IN MY CHAIR!"
said the Great Big Bear in his great,
rough, gruff voice.
And the careless Goldilocks had squatted
down the soft cushion of the Middle-
sized Bear. "SOMEBODY HAS BEEN SITTING IN
MY CHAIR!"
said the Middle-sized Bear in his
middle-sized voice. "
SOMEBODY HAS BEEN SITTING IN MY CHAIR, AND
HAS SAT THE BOTTOM THROUGH!"
said the Little Wee Bear in his little wee
voice.
Then the Three Bears thought they had
better make further search in case it
was a burglar, so they went upstairs into
their bedchamber.
Now Goldilocks had pulled the pillow of
the Great Big Bear out of its place. "
SOMEBODY HAS BEEN LYING IN MY BED!"
said the Great Big Bear in his great,
rough, gruff voice.
And Goldilocks had pulled the bolster of
the Middle-sized Bear out of its
place. "SOMEBODY HAS BEEN LYING IN MY
BED!"
said the Middle-sized Bear in his
middle-sized voice.
But when the Little Wee Bear came to look
at his bed, there was the bolster in
its place! And the pillow was in its place
upon the bolster!
And upon the pillow——?
There was Goldilocks's yellow head—which
was not in its place, for she had no
business there. "SOMEBODY HAS BEEN LYING
IN MY BED,—AND HERE SHE IS STILL!"
said the Little Wee Bear in his little wee
voice.
Now Goldilocks had heard in her sleep the
great, rough, gruff voice of the
Great Big Bear; but she was so fast asleep
that it was no more to her than the
roaring of wind, or the rumbling of
thunder.
And she had heard the middle-sized voice
of the Middle-sized Bear, but it was
only as if she had heard some one speaking
in a dream.
But when she heard the little wee voice of
the Little Wee Bear, it was so
sharp, and so shrill, that it awakened her
at once.
Up she started, and when she saw the Three
Bears on one side of the bed, she
tumbled herself out at the other, and ran
to the window.
Now the window was open, because the
Bears, like good, tidy Bears, as they
were, always opened their bedchamber
window when they got up in the morning.
So naughty, frightened little Goldilocks
jumped;
and whether she broke her neck in the
fall, or ran into the wood and was lost
there, or found her way out of the wood
and got whipped for being a bad girl
and playing truant, no one can say.
But the Three Bears never saw anything
more of her.